

# **Devi Babu**Financial Lead Analyst

## **My Contact**

devibabu040@gmail.com

**(** 8148282803

Chennai

#### **Hard Skill**

- Financial modeling and reporting
- · Data mining and analysis
- · Financial accounting
- Business valuation
- SAP and MS Suite proficiency
- · Analytical skills
- Management Skills

#### **Soft Skill**

- Team Management
- · Client management
- Work Ethic
- Communication
- Multi-tasking
- Presentation
- Cross Functional teams
- Team work
- Time management
- · Adaptability
- Emotional Intelligence

#### **Education Background**

- University of Madras
   Masters in Business Administration
   Completed in 2011
- University of Madras
   Masters in English Literature
   Completed in 2007
- RVG Arts and science college Bachelor of English Literature Completed in 2005

#### **About Me**

Dedicated and detail-oriented Financial Lead Analyst with 13 years of experience with multiple domain. Eager to apply proven-budget maximization skills for Accounts Receivable in Cash application, deduction, invoicing, telecom Billing, team monitoring, maintaining the reports, and completing client billing and reconciliations. Special interest in new learning and skills.

### **Professional Experience**

Iopex Technologies | Financial Senior Analyst

Dec 2019 - May 2023. I Telecom Billing Project

- Set goals, develop metrics and report to help the team understand its value and progress.
- Manage performance of the team and timely processing.
- Set and review KRA's for the team, align the goals to the overall objectives
  of the organisation/ Client. Would have regular daily meetings with
  Client..
- Develop SOP and training manuals, created Entitlement study for new project. Capacity/ resource planning and management.
- Maintained team productivity tracker, attendance tracker, score card.

## Accenture | General Accounting Operations Analyst Feb 2016 - Nov 2019 | OTC Project

- Experienced in accounts receivable O2C end to end process with special focus on: Cash application, Dispute management, collections, customer service, invoice and billing.
- Accounts receivable functions including invoice creation, cash application, research and investigation of chargeback's including discrepancies, accounts receivable reconciliations.

## Tata Consultancy services I Senior Processor

OCt 2010 - Nov 2013. I OTC Project

- Managing incoming payments, clearing of accounts receivables and investigated cash applications discrepancies based on invoice. Identify and rectify unidentified cash.
- Created spreadsheets to enhance tracking of accounts receivables.

#### **HDFC SLIC I Operations Officer**

Sep 2007 - Aug 2010 I Insurance Hub-operations

- Handling Operations –Looking New Business Process, Policy servicing and Zonal Helpdesk.
- Coordination Maintaining coordination with sales and Branch teams for hassle free working.
- Management- Managing and handling coordinators, Outsourcing staffs, DMC and Dispatch department staff regarding product training and customer queries.
- Processing AML and KYC documents for insurance approval.

## **Achievements**

2016 - 2019

Cash application-Resolved unidentified money worth over \$1.2 million.

2019 - 2023

Identified Revenue leakage in billing and projects worth over \$2.8 million.